长途飞行吗
Long flight?
简直没完没了  还有多远
Endless. How much further?
还有些时间
You have some time.
如果想睡觉  请随意  先生
If you want to sleep, go ahead, sir.
我给你弄了杯咖啡
Hey! I made some coffee for you.
失眠者的力量来源
It's insomniac strength.
你已经连续四天晚上没睡觉了
This is the fourth night in a row that you haven't slept.
-出什么事了  -我不知道
- Something wrong? - I don't know.
可能我的潜意识迫切想要我
Maybe my subconscious has a pressing need to...
查看脸书网上谁给我点赞了
catch up on my facebook likes.
-玛莎  早上好  -早上好  亲爱的
- Martha, good morning. - Ah. Good morning, darling.
-来点早餐吗  -不  谢谢
- Would you like some breakfast? - No, thank you.
为了保持清醒  我要禁食
I'm, uh, fasting for clarity.
我受邀为斯托帕德 的新戏做试演
I have been asked to read for the new Stoppard play.
有什么问题
So what's the problem?
我已经很久没有参加试镜了
Well, I haven't auditioned for anything in ages.
我需要知道我的天赋
I think I need to decide if that particular train
是否还依然存在
has left the station.
"凯萨琳·贝克特女士收"  这是什么
"Ms. Katherine beckett"? What's this?
有个前男友要结婚了
Oh, an ex is getting married.
你还记得威尔·索伦森吗
Do you remember Will Sorenson?
-你那个联调局前男友吗  -是的
- Your old F.B.I. Squeeze? - Yeah.
真是幸运  我出现在你生活中
Oh, man. I'm so lucky I came along
-拯救你脱离苦海  -等等  你拯救了我吗
- and saved you from that life. - Wait. You saved me?
拜托  你自己也得承认他无聊透了
Come on. Even you have to admit he was boring.
像有线卫星公众事务网络一样无聊
Like, C-SPAN boring.
你凭什么认为
You know, what makes you think
如果你不出现  我还会和索伦森在一起呢
that I would be with Sorenson if you hadn't come along?
好吧  那你会在哪
All right, where would you be?
-如果没有你在周围捣乱  -是的
- If you weren't around to distract me? - Yeah.
我可能会成为...
Um, I would probably be...
我自己分局的警监
captain of my own precinct.
-厉害  -没错
- Wow. - Yeah.
好吧  如果我没有被你迷住的话
Okay. Had I not been bewitched by you,
现在我可能在写第二本普利策得奖作品了
I think by now I'd be working on my second Pulitzer.
-这么说我们拖彼此的后腿了  -糟透了
- So we're bad for each other, huh? - The worst.
如果我们从未相遇的话可能会更好
I guess we'd both be better off if we'd never met.
就像是电影《美好人生》
It's like "It's a wonderful life."
每次你电话一响  就意味着有人遇害了
Every time your phone rings, a victim gets their wings.
他的名字叫马提亚斯·甘斯勒
His name is Mathias Gensler.
他的护照显示他是瑞士籍公民
His passport indicates that he is a Swiss national.
目击者称  两个蒙面人
Witnesses said that two masked men
袭击了司机和甘斯勒
attacked both the driver and Gensler
然后把甘斯勒先生的手腕砍下来
before cutting a silver briefcase
抢走了和他拷在一起的银色公文包
handcuffed to Mr. Gensler's wrist.
这是一起埋伏  作案的人
So this was an ambush. Whoever did this
知道他随身携带着这个公文包
knew that he had that case with him.
看起来袭击者驾驶一辆
Looks like the attackers fled
无牌照的新型奔驰车逃跑的
in a late model G-Wagon, no plates.
他衬衣上是鞋印吗
Is that a boot print on his shirt?
凶手一定踩着他不让他起身
The killer must have held him down with his foot.
公文包里有什么
So what was in the case?
核启动代码  还是致命病毒
Nuclear launch codes? Deadly virus?
我们还不知道  司机的记录显示
We don't know yet. The driver's log shows
从特波罗机场接到甘斯勒先生
that Mr. Gensler was picked up at Teterboro airport
他是从瑞士来的私人包机上下来的
after arriving on a private charter flight from Switzerland.
车送他去哪里
And where was the car taking him?
这只显示了接他的地点
The manifest only lists the pickup.
-给租车公司打电话了吗  -没人可以找
- You call the car company? - Uh, there's no one to call.
那个司机  伦佐·康拉德  他就是老板
The driver -- Renzo Conrad -- owned the service.
他一个人单干
He was a one-man band.
说到单干  你的搭档呢
Speaking of "One-man band," where's your partner?
是啊  还有蕾妮呢
Yeah! And Lanie.
等等
Wait! Wait.
我们来了  我们刚才...
We're here. We were just, uh...
-有点堵车  -是的
- Stuck in traffic. - Yeah.
你跟罗密欧汇报一下情况
Why don't you bring Romeo here up to speed
然后联系一下瑞士领事馆
and contact the Swiss consulate.
也许他们知道甘斯勒要干什么
Maybe they know what Gensler was up to.
卡塞尔  你在对我的尸体做什么
Castle, what are you doing with my body?
假装不认识他好了
Just pretend like you don't know him.
贝克特  这不是土
Beckett, this is not dirt.
是打火石  少许碳
It's flint... hints of carbon.
这是煤
That's coal.
-是粉末状未经提炼的煤  -然后呢
- It's pulverized, unrefined coal. - So?
我曾在一部早期的
So I used a clue like this
斯道姆小说里写过一个类似的线索
in one of my early Derrick Storm books.
除了在燃煤发电厂
It's very unusual to find unrefined coal
未经提炼的煤是很罕见的
outside a Coal-Fired power plant.
城里的燃煤发电厂
All the coal plants in the city are either
要么被关闭  要么转型了
shut down or converted.
是的  但是有的厂子依然存在
Right, but some of them are still standing.
在哈德森就有个被废弃的工厂
There's an abandoned one on Hudson
他们准备把它建成一个购物中心
they're gonna turn into a shopping mall.
煤灰可能从别的地方来的
Coal dust could have come from a lot of places.
废弃的燃煤发电厂
An abandoned plant would be a perfect place
是突袭的完美场所
to launch a strike like this.
蕾妮  你去鉴证组
Lanie, why don't you get C.S.U. Techs
检测一下死者衬衫上的残留物
to test the substance on the victim's shirt?
我们去特波罗机场查一下那架飞机
We gotta go to Teterboro and look into that flight.
那个燃煤发电厂正顺路
And that coal plant is right on the way.
好吧
Fine.
我们顺路去一下那个发电厂
We'll stop off at the coal plant.
你想去吗
So you thinking about going?
去哪
Going where?
索伦森的婚礼
Sorenson's wedding.
重温一下往日情怀
Take a little trip down memory lane.
我认为这不是个好主意
I don't think that's such a good idea.
为什么不呢
Why not?
我还没准备好参加别人的婚礼
I'm not really ready for someone else's perfect day.
如果可以改变过去  我愿意做任何事
You know I'd give anything to change what happened, right?
是的  我知道
Yeah, I know you would.
卡塞尔
Castle.
你说得对
You were right.
凶手的奔驰车在这
The shooter's G-Wagon's here.
埃斯波  我需要支援到哈德森燃煤厂来
Espo, hey. I need backup at the Hudson river coal plant.
公文包在那
There's the case.
里面有什么
What's in it?
像是某种手工艺品
Some kind of artifact.
想必是值钱东西才值得去杀人灭口
Must be valuable if it was worth killing over.
卡塞尔  你在干嘛
Castle, what are you --
蹲下
Get down!
为什么你总是这么手贱
Why do you always have to touch everything?
我以为你喜欢我这点
I thought you liked that about me.
快跑
Move!
贝克特
Beckett?
Beckett?!
伙计们
Guys. Hey, guys.
贝克特出事了
Beckett's in trouble.
我逃了出来  但她的车不见了
I got away, but her car is missing.
-我想她被绑架了  -警监
- I think she was abducted. - Uh, Captain?
你没事了  你回来了
You're okay! You made it back.
贝克特警监  这个人说你出事了
Captain Beckett, this guy claims you're in trouble.
-警监  -你认识他吗
- Captain? - You know him?
我从没见过这个人
I've never seen this man before in my life.
从没见过我  好吧  真好笑
Never seen me before? Okay, that's very funny.
我只是很高兴你没事  你是怎么回来的
I'm just glad you're okay. How did you get back here?
-你说什么  -从发电厂回来
- Excuse me? - From the power plant.
我们遭遇枪战  顺便说句  这套衣服不错
We were being shot at. That's a nice suit, by the way.
不管你是谁  你该离开这了
Whoever you are, I think you better leave.
-不管我是谁  -走吧  老兄
- Whoever I am? - Come on, pal.
不管你嗑什么了  如果你悄悄离开这
Ow! Whatever trip you're on, if you leave quietly,
我们可以当什么事都没发生过
I'm sure we can forget this ever happened.
好了  我懂了  你们在整我
Okay! Whoa-ho! I get it. You guys are punking me.
抱歉  就像我生日那次
Sorry. Just like, uh, my birthday.
这招不错  你们怎么做到那么逼真的
This is good. How did you stage that?
双尸枪击案  那只断手
The double shooting, the severed hand,
衬衣上的煤灰
coal dust on the shirt?
他刚刚描述了案发现场
He just described our crime scene.
你从哪得到这些信息的
Where did you get that information?
从案发现场得到的  我跟你们三个
From being... at the crime scene with...
一起去的啊
all of you.
警监  我们五分钟前才拿到
Captain, we only got the forensics
法医的关于煤灰报告
about the coal dust five minutes ago.
你是怎么知道这么多案件细节的
And how do you know so much about this case?
凯特  你们骗到我了  玩笑到此为止
Kate, okay, you know what? You got me. Joke's over.
你说的没错  到此为止了
You're right. It is.
伙计们
Guys!
真的假的  这是怎么回事
Seriously, what's going on here?
理查德·卡塞尔先生  原来你是个小说家
Mr. Richard Castle. Ha, you're a novelist.
要不你给我们讲个故事
Why don't you tell us a story
讲讲早上四点至六点之间你在哪
about where you were between 4:00 and 6:00 A.M.?
我和贝克特在床上
In bed with Beckett.
你还是不要这样诋毁警监吧
Maybe you shouldn't talk about the captain like that.
你是怎么知道煤灰的事
How did you know about the coal dust?
故事就是从那开始的  就在那个工厂
Well, that's where all this started, at the plant.
在那发生了
There was --
发生了爆炸
There was an explosion.
我一定是昏迷了  这是个梦境
I must have gotten knocked out. This is a dream.
你们只是我大脑创造出来的
Okay? You guys are just creations of my psyche.
我这是在解决心理问题
This is me just working out some issues.
所以你们不认识我  因为你们并不存在
That's why you don't know me, because you aren't real.
你们知道吗  我可以证明
And you know what? I can prove it.
众所周知
Well-known fact,
在梦境里是看不清字的
it's impossible to read in a dream.
'理查德·卡塞尔  又名理查德·罗杰斯'
"Richard Castle, A.K.A. Richard Rodgers."
你吓着我了
You had me worried there.
我刚刚还真以为我不存在呢
For a second, I thought I didn't exist.
打住打住
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Hey --
这里写着我跳上了梅西百货的游行花车
It says here I jumped on a Macy's parade float
接着和伊迪娜·门泽尔合唱了《随他吧》
and sang "Let it go" with Idina Menzel
然后坐着热气球在中央公园裸体着陆了
and then landed a hot-air balloon naked in central park?
我没做过这些  伙计们
I didn't do these things, guys.
拜托  我绝不会跟人合唱《随他吧》的
Come on. I would never sing "Let it go" as a duet.
卡塞尔先生  如果你告诉我们
Mr. Castle, this is gonna go much easier for you
你对于谋杀案有什么了解  事情会简单很多
if you just tell us what you know about those murders.
好吧  凯特
Okay, Kate? Kate!
这家伙疯了
This guy's nuts.
出来
Come on.
拜托了  跟我谈谈
Please, just talk to me.
坐下  不然我要扣押你了
Sit down, or I'll have to restrain you.
我知道你在那  因为通常我都在你旁边
I know you're in there, because usually I'm right beside you.
卡塞尔先生  坐下
Mr. Castle, sit down.
我来处理
I'll handle this.
你确定吗  警监
You sure, Captain?
卡塞尔先生  我们暂时假设
Mr. Castle, let's just say for a moment
我们的确见过彼此吧
that you and I did meet each other.
我们在哪里见过
Where would that have been?
在我的签售会上  你来找我
At my book party. You came to me.
你向我咨询一件模仿谋杀案
You asked me to consult on a copycat murder.
就在六年前  当时你还是短发
It was six years ago. Your hair was short then.
短发的你很可爱
It was adorable.
六年前啊
Six years ago, huh?
资料上说和你见面的是麦克纳提警探
Well, it says here that you met with a Detective McNulty.
显然是你帮助他破了案子
Apparently you helped him solve the case.
不  凯特  是你
No -- no, no, no. Kate, it was -- it was you.
好吧  今天早上我在你身边醒过来
All right. Okay, I -- I woke up next to you this morning.
这不是我幻想出来的
I'm not imagining that.
我很抱歉  卡塞尔先生
I-I'm sorry, Mr. Castle.
我们俩没有在交往
We don't have a relationship.
在今天之前  我们从没见过面
Before today, you and I have never met.
你想打电话叫谁来接你吗
Now, is there someone that you would like to call?
这个签名是送给谁的
Who should I make this out to?
是凯文  罗杰斯夫人
Uh, Kevin, Mrs, Rodgers.
好的  凯文
All right, Kevin.
您在《玫瑰舞后》饰演的玫瑰  完美无瑕
Your Mama Rose in "Gypsy" -- perfection!
谢谢  你真是个善良又贴心的孩子
Ah, thank you. You are a dear, sweet boy.
那第三个托尼奖本该是您的
You were robbed of that third Tony.
-过奖了  -母亲
- Oh, well. - Mother?
理查德
Richard!
亲爱的  你样子好糟
Darling, you look like hell.
谢天谢地  你最懂我了
Thank god. You know me.
不  别这样  亲爱的你浑身脏兮兮的
No, no, no. Please. Darling, you're filthy.
你妈妈给你做不在场证明算你走运
You're lucky your mama could alibi you out for the murder.
他只在纸上杀人
Oh, he only kills on paper.
你要知道来警察局
And I'll have you know that coming down
把我成年的儿子弄出监狱
to the police station to get my grown son out of prison
是我现在最没时间做的事
is the last thing I have time for.
你很清楚我们还有两天就开业了
You know full well we open in two days.
-开什么业  -"梅姑"啊
- We open what? - "MAME"!
我的"梅姑"要重新开业
My revival of "Auntie mame."
你昨晚到底嗨到什么程度啊
Exactly how hard did you party last night?
显然非常非常嗨
Apparently very, very hard.
这可不是好事
Oh, that can't be good.
来吧  孩子  过来  亲爱的
Come on, kiddo. Come on. Oh, dear.
别担心  亲爱的
Don't worry, darling.
到家就好了
Once you're home, you'll feel much better.
天啊  母亲
Oh, my god, mother!
你把我家怎么了
What have you done with my place?
理查德  这事我们已经聊过了
Oh, Richard. We have talked abou this!
现在咱们是合缴贷款  这是咱俩的家
Now that we share the mortgage, it is our place.
而且  既然你的大部分存款都没了...
And since you have lost most of your life savings...
啥  存款没了  怎么没的
Whoa! Lost my savings? How?
你投资失败啊  大都花在美女和赛马上了
You invested poorly... mostly blondes and racehorses.
而且你这伟大的美国小说
And it's not as if your great american novel here
也没有多畅销
is flying off the shelves.
《有限之笑》  我没写过这书  这...
"Finite laughter"? I did not write this. This...
"巴布柯克是个小男人  有着大梦想的小男人
"Babcock was a small man, a small man with large dreams,
而其中的一个梦想就是贝蒂"  太烂了
and one of those dreams was Betty." This is awful!
评论家也是这么说的
Exactly what the critics said.
但我很高兴客观角度总算让你有点自知之明了
But I am pleased to see that distance has given you some perspective.
-很好  -爸
- Good. - Oh, hey, dad.
看来你是保释了
I see you made bail.
阿丽克西斯  你的头发  什么时候弄的
Alexis, your hair! When did you do that?!
三年前
Uh, three years ago.
-我搬去洛杉矶之前就弄了  -洛杉矶
- Before I moved to L.A. - L.A.?!
理查德  别找茬  阿丽克西斯就回来待几天
Richard, don't start. Alexis is here for a few days.
她可是专程从拯救世界的大业中抽出时间
She's taking time off from saving the world
-来参加我的开幕之夜的  -够了
- to come to my opening night. - Okay.
好吧  够了
Okay, that's it.
够了  我受够了
That's it. I'm done.
奶奶  他没事吧
Grandma, is he ok?
他昨晚过得不容易
He had a rough night.
不管这都是怎么回事
Whatever... all this is,
昏迷  做梦  或是什么诡异的幻觉
Coma, a dream, wired hallucination,
就算只是披萨消化不良
Or, even just a undigested pisa
我要结束这一切
I'm ending it.
该醒醒了
It's time to wake up.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我以前从没做过这样的梦
I've never had a dream like this before.
-我怎么还没醒  -也许这不是梦
- Why aren't I waking up? - Maybe it's not a dream.
也许你穿越到什么平行宇宙里去了
Maybe you traveled into some alternate universe.
阿丽克西斯  别讽刺你老爸
Oh, Alexis, don't tease your father.
亲爱的  要不你去躺会儿吧
Darling, Maybe you'd just better lie down.
对  可能真该躺会儿
Yeah, maybe I should.
小查德
Hey, Richie.
照你说的  我用了你藏的钥匙
I used your hidden key like you said.
你是谁
Who are you?
要玩这个游戏吗
Oh, is that what we're playing?
好啊
Okay. Oh!
我在汽车站看到了你  先生
I saw you at the bus stop, mister,
于是便尾随你回了家
And I followed you home.
好吧  显然我们认识  切尔西吗
Okay, obviously we know each other...Chelsea?
真是我人生中最快乐的两周
Oh, it was the funnest two weeks of my life.
好吧  说真的  我...
Okay, real...I... oh, I...
-我真不行  -你当然行  你行的
- I-I really can't do this. - Sure, you can. Sure, you can.
我包里有几片伟哥
I got a couple little blue pills in my purse.
哦不不  我是说  不...
Oh. No... no, I mean... no, I just... I, uh...
我得继续工作了
I-I have to get back to work.
听着  你看起来是个可爱的年轻的...
Look, you seem like a... a lovely young... mm?
非常年轻的女人  可我想你该走了
Young woman, but I-I-I, um, I think you should go.
真的假的
Seriously?
你们这些作家还真奇怪
You writers are so strange.
就好像突然之间  我穿过了一扇门
It was like suddenly I waed through a doorway
那边的人我都认识  可一切都不一样了
where I knew everyone, but everything was different.
我老婆嫁给了别的男人
My wife was married to another man.
我回到家  我父母都没认出我来
I came back home, and my parents didn't recognize me.
他们根本不认识我
They didn't know me.
早上好  亲爱的
Well, good morning, darling.
今天感觉好点了吗
Are you feeling better today?
好多了  我知道是怎么回事了
Much, because I know what's going on.
我知道我为什么在这里了  是这个
I know why I'm here. It's this.
"瑞士考古团队发现了古印加人手工艺品"
"Swi archaeological team discovers ancient incan artifact"?
不是随便什么手工艺品  从记号来看
Not just any artifact. Given its markings,
一些神秘主义者相信
some mystics believe that it's connected
它与印加人通往诸神之地的大门有关
to the incan gateway to the gods,
通过那扇门  萨满教巫师
A doorway through which shamans
可以穿越到另一个时空去
were known to travel into other rea.
老爸  我那是开玩笑的
Dad, I was joking.
别告诉我你相信这些
Please don't tell me you believe this.
阿莱克西斯  我当时就拿着它
Alexis, I was holding this.
就在那时候
And at right at the moment,
手榴弹滚到了我们之间
as the grenade was rolling between us,
我在想  也许我配不上她
I was thinking maybe I wasn't good for her.
如果我们从未相遇  贝克特也许会过得更好
Maybe Beckett would be happier if we had never met.
就是这个发生了改变  这就是我所在的世界
That's what changed. That's where I am...
一个我们从未相遇过的世界
In a world where we never met.
就好像过去的六年从未发生过
It's like the last six years didn't happen.
贝克特是谁
Who... who's Beckett?
没错  你不知道她是谁
Exactly. You don't know who she is,
因为我们从未相遇  我也没写过妮奇·希特小说
Because she and I never met, so I didn't write "Nikki heat,"
我只写出了那堆垃圾
I wrote that godawful piece of trash instead,
由于收入很少
and with less money coming in,
你不得不去外面打拼  追求成功
you were forced to go out and be successful.
我成功是因为我有才
I found success because of my boundless talent.
-而出于某种原因  我们疏远了  -某种原因
- And somehow we drifted apart. - Somehow?
不是我疯了  只是这里不是我的世界
I'm not crazy. This is not my world.
-我要回家  -你要怎么回
- I need to get back home. - How do you intend to do that?
我要帮这个世界的贝克特找到那个工艺品
By helping this world's Beckett find that artifact
这样我就能回到我的现实了
so I can get back to my reality.
所以我才和妈妈住
This is why I live with mom.
原来你是我的粉丝啊
So you're a fan.
我还以为你不知道我呢
And here I thought you didn't know me.
我不知道  我是说之前不知道
Yeah, I don't. I mean, I didn't. I --
你没认出来那个神经错乱的我吧
Didn't recognize me in my deranged state?
我应该道歉
Listen... I have to apologize.
我的所作所为肯定让你以为我是疯了
How I acted, you must have thought I was crazy.
没错  因为你就是疯了
Well, yeah, that's because you were.
这是因为我正在写的一本新书
Yeah. It's this new book I've been working on.
我一直在创作
I have been working nonstop.
我不停的喝咖啡
I mean, I have been drinking coffee,
吃安定  我都几天没睡了
popping NoDoz, I haven't slept in days,
而且更糟的是
and to make matters worse...
书里有个新人物  是以你为原型塑造的
There's a new character. I-I kind of based her on you.
根据我从新闻上对你的了解
What I -- what I read about you.
她聪明机智  发奋图强
So she's savvy and smart and driven,
而且我爱上了她
and I have fallen in love with her.
我和她一起吃饭  睡觉
I mean, I eat with her, I sleep with her --
但我知道了  你不是她
but I know you are not her.
这些都不能解释
You know, none of this explains
你为什么对案发现场如此了解
how you know so much about the crime scene.
我有个警用电台
I have a police scanner,
我在跟进这件案子
and I was tracking the investigation.
事实上  这正是我来的原因  警监
Actually, that's why I'm here, captain.
我知道手提箱里装的什么
I know what was in the briefcase,
我知道它去了哪
I know where it's going,
而且我想我知道是谁拿的
and I think I know who took it.
你怎么知道的
And how do you know all that?
说来话长  但我真知道
It's complicated, but... I do.
警监
Hey, captain.
他来这儿干嘛
What's he doing here?
我不知道
I'm not sure.
好吧  快递公司回复了
Okay. So, uh, I heard back from the courier company.
原来死者是在运送一件
Turns out our victim was transporting --
古老的印加工艺品
An ancient incan artifact.
没错  而且是要送去
Yeah. And, uh, it was on its way --
纽约帕利塞兹的
To the lamont-doherty laboratories
拉蒙-多哈堤实验室做研究
in palisades, new york, for study.
科学家认为它是陨石打造的
Scientists believe it was fashioned from a meteorite,
但是传统扫描仪都无法穿透它
but it's proven impenetrable to conventional scans.
我怎么知道的
How did I know all this?
我当过犯罪小说家  现在也有些线人
I used to be a crime novelist, and I still have a few sources.
警监  死者就是因为它被杀的
Captain, this is what your victims were killed for.
为什么会有人为这东西杀人
And why would someone kill for this?
实验室的人说这样的古董
Well, the folks at the lab said an object like that
对收藏家来说是无价之宝
would be invaluable to any collector.
卡塞尔先生  你说你知道是谁拿走了它
Mr. Castle, you said that you might know who took it.
我虽然不确定那人是谁
Not exactly who, but...
但我知道与谁有关
I know who was involved.
租赁车要去接甘斯勒
So the car service was going to pick up Gensler,
即是送货员  接人的地点是这里的机场
the courier, from the airport here,
送他去这里的实验室  基本是向北的
take him to the lab here -- basically north.
但出于某种原因  他们被袭击时
Yet for some reason, when they were attacked,
-却在西班牙哈莱姆区  -反方向
- they ended up here in Spanish Harlem. - The opposite way.
没错  所以要么是司机
Yes. So either this driver
毫无方向感可言
had a terrible sense of direction...
要么就是司机参与了其中
Or he was in on it.
也许是他的同伴杀他是为灭口
And maybe his partners killed him to silence him.
莱恩警探  去详细调查这个司机
Detective Ryan, get me everything you can on that driver.
你帮了大忙  卡塞尔先生
That was surprisingly helpful, Mr. Castle.
我可不可以  在这儿待着
Do you mind if I... hang around,
-跟进一下案件  -休息室在那边
- see how this turns out? - Mm-hmm. Breakroom's over there.
我知道
I know.
写东西的  告诉我
Yo, writer boy, tell me how you know
-你怎么知道燃煤工厂的事的  -什么
- about that coal plant. - What?
就是你昨天来时提到的那个
The one you were talking about when you came in yesterday.
警监让我来问问你
Captain had me check it out.
你知道我发现了什么吗
You know what I found?
轮胎印
Tire tracks.
和我们在案发现场发现的轮胎印一模一样
The same tire tracks that we found at our crime scene.
你知道犯人把那里当作
Now, you knew that our doers were using it
中转站  而你知道的唯一原因
as a staging ground, and the only way
就是因为你有参与其中
you would know that is if you were involved.
好吧  我一般不会告诉别人的  不过
Okay, fine. I don't usually like to tell people this,
我有超能力
but I have a gift.
-我能看出一些事  -看出一些事
- I know things. - You know things?
你我昨天是第一次见面没错吧
You and I haven't met before yesterday, correct?
-没错  -那我是怎么能知道
- Yeah. - So then how would I know
你喜欢一个女人
that you had a thing with a woman
她姓名的缩写是L.P.
whose initials were... L.P.?
而且我又怎么知道
And how would I know that
她走向了下段感情你却放不下呢
she moved on and you can't?
莱恩就是个大嘴巴  是他告诉你的
Ryan has a big, fat mouth. That's how you know.
怎么回事呢  不敢做出承诺吗
What happened? Commitment issues?
哥们  有新发现
Hey, man. We got something.
在他被杀前四天里
Okay, so over the last four days before he was killed,
司机曾经
our driver made a --
司机曾经多次打给
Our driver made a series of phone calls
一家餐厅里的公用电话
to a pay phone located inside of a restaurant.
问题在于  那家店已经
The only problem is, the place has been shut down
-关门好几个月了  -他要打给谁
- the past couple of months. - Who was he calling?
不知道  不过看这个
I have no idea, but check it out --
那家废弃餐厅   鸟人
The deserted restaurant, El Chozo,
也许就是他想去的地方
maybe that's where he was headed.
离SUV被袭击的地点不远
It's right near where the S.U.V. was attacked.
好吧  去那看看  找找线索
All right, get up there. See what you can find.
警监  我能不能跟着一起去
Uh, captain, would it be possible for me to ride along?
-只是为写书做点研究  -他开玩笑吗
- Uh, strictly for research purposes. - Is he kidding?
我只是不愿错过观察的机会
I would just love the chance to observe,
为我的书收集点细节素材
get some details for my book.
警监  我们可以带着他
Yeah, sure, cap, we'll take him along.
-搞什么啊  -他是玛莎·罗杰斯的儿子
- What the... - Dude, that's Martha Rodgers' son.
他可以给我们弄到贵宾票
He can get us house seats.
-你能弄到贵宾票对吧  -没  问题
- You can get us house seats, right? - Ab...solutely.
好吧  但是要听话  不要碍事
Okay. But do as they say and don't interfere.
好了  走吧我的贵宾票
Come on. Let's go, house seats.
你们警监
So the captain --
她有男朋友吗
is she seeing anyone?
谈过几个  没有到认真的地步
She has boyfriends. Nothing serious.
怎么  作家小子
Why, writer boy?
你难道觉得自己有机会追到她
What, you think you have a chance with her?
还有你都干了些什么
And what are you doing,
竟然口无遮拦地对外人说别人的私生活
telling crazy over here about everyone's private life?
-我吗  -对
- Me? - Yeah.
-你跟他说了蕾妮和我的事  -不
- You told him about Lanie and me. - No --
不不不  我没有
No. No, no, no, I didn't!
我跟你们说  我有种天赋
I'm telling you -- I have a gift, all right?
每当看到某个人  我就能看出一些事
I look at people, and I see things.
是吗
Yeah, okay.
你看看我  能看出什么来
What do you see when you look at me?
蜂蜜牛奶和雀斑
Honeymilk and freckles.
不是吧
No!
是珍妮·奥马利
That's Jenny O'malley.
是的  她以前经常给我做蜂蜜牛奶
Yeah, she used to make me honeymilk.
她本来会成为我的妻子
She could have been the one.
-本来会  -是的
- Could have? - Yeah...
贝克特升任警监后  我们的案子数量翻了倍
Well, when Beckett was promoted to captain, our caseload doubled.
我没时间陪她
I guess I-I never had time for her.
或许你应该给她打个电话
Maybe you should give her a call.
或许你应该管好你自己的事
Maybe you should mind your own business.
好了  听好规矩
All right. Here are the rules --
待在车里  否则我就向你开枪  明白了吗
Stay in the car, or I shoot you. Got it?
能给我留个窗缝吗
You want to crack a window for me?
简直不敢相信警监让我们照顾这蠢货
I can't believe the captain's making us babysit this nutjob.
他还好啦
He's not so bad.
太棒了
Oh, yes.
好了
Okay...
带我回家
Take me home.
要显灵啊
Come on...
交出来  否则就杀了你
Hand it over, or you die.
谁派你来的  你都知道什么
Who sent you? What do you know?
没人派我来  没人  是它送我来的
Nobody sent me. Nobody. It just -- this -- it sent me.
这个东西  是它  我看到了一束蓝光
The object, it sent me. I saw a blue light,
然后我就来这了
and I ended up here.
纽约警察  马上把刀放下
NYPD! Dropour knife now!
不要
No!
搞什么  伙计
What the hell, man?
你应该在车里等着的
You were supposed to wait in the car.
还有关系吗  都碎了
What does it matter now? It's broken!
我回不了家了
Now I'm never getting home.
一辈子都被困在这了
Now I'm stuck here in this life.
可真的那个是不会碎的
But the real one would never...break.
这是个假的  这是个假的
This is a fake! This is a fake.
你从哪得到的  真的在哪里
Where did you get this, and where's the real one?
把他也拷上
Cuff him, too.
你觉得你在做什么
What the hell do you think you were doing?
你会害死自己的
You could have gotten yourself killed.
我有后援  而且我的确帮忙抓到了嫌犯
I had backup. And I did help capture a suspect.
不  你应该只是随行  在一边观望
No, you were supposed to accompany and observe,
-而不是参与和...  -干扰
- not participate and... - Annoy.
让我的人身处险境
Risk my people's lives.
经过上午的闹剧后
Now, after this morning's antics,
我希望你能表现得好一些
I expected you to be on your best behavior.
-其实  我已经表现得很好了  -什么事
- Actually, that kind of is my best behavior. - What?
我只是在欣赏你们的争论
Oh, I'm just enjoying the show.
嫌犯名字是玛利亚·桑切斯
Our suspect's name is Maria Sanchez.
她被秘鲁政府通缉了
She's wanted by the Peruvian government
跟政府大楼的爆炸案有关
in connection with the bombings at a government building,
还有偷窃和非法交易手工艺品
not to mention the theft and trafficking of stolen artifacts.
那就是她了  她是幕后黑手
Then that's her, and she's behind it.
我们得跟她谈谈
We need to talk to her.
不  卡塞尔先生  是他们去跟她谈
No, Mr. Castle, they need to talk to her.
你该回家了  这案子没你的事了
You need to go home. You're done with this case.
-但  -我没因为妨碍执法拘捕你  算你走运
- But... - You're lucky I don't arrest you for obstruction.
警官  请送卡塞尔先生进电梯
Officer, please escort Mr. Castle to the elevator.
-我希望他离开  -你不明白
- I want him gone. - You don't understand.
我需要找到这个手工艺品
I need to find this artifact.
贝克特  求你了
Beckett! Please!
什么事  埃斯波西托警探
Yes, Detective Esposito?
你不会让他影响到你吧
You're not letting him get to him, are you?
你不是还有案子要破吗
Don't you have a case to close?
你们管这叫走私
You call it smuggling.
我们这是把自己的东西拿回来
We call it taking back our rightful legacy.
那件手工品在我们萨满教的人看来是很神圣的
That artifact was considered divine by our Shamans
而且是属于我们印加人的
and belongs to the Incan people.
为了这个东西值得杀死两个人吗
Was that legacy worth the lives of two men?
不  计划不是这样的
No, that wasn't the plan.
那计划是什么样的  玛利亚
Then what was the plan, Maria?
快点  直接问她那工艺品在哪就行了
Come on. Just ask where the artifact is.
我的堂兄  伦佐  他是司机
My cousin Renzo -- he was the driver.
他在送货人的水里放了镇定剂
He put sedatives in the courier's water
好让他昏迷过去
to knock him out.
甘斯勒睡着后  我们就会把他
Once Gensler was asleep, we were going to
带到饭店  然后把手提箱调包
bring him to the restaurant and switch the cases.
没人会受伤
No one was supposed to get hurt.
但有人袭击了他们  拿走了它
But someone attacked them. Someone else took it.
你不知道它在哪
You don't know where it is?
袭击发生在离饭店不远的地方
That attack happened just a few blocks from the restaurant.
他们怎么知道车会去那
How did they know the car was gonna be there?
还有谁知道这事  玛利亚
Who else was involved, Maria?
除了你和伦佐
Who else besides you and Renzo
还有谁知道更改了线路
knew about the change in route?
没人
No one.
除了机场那个人
Except the guy at the airport.
-什么人  -什么人
- What guy? - What guy?
只有伦佐接到甘斯勒这个计划才能成功
The plan only worked if Renzo made the pickup.
但是送货人用的是另一家公司的租车服务
But the courier, Gensler, was using another car service.
所以我们贿赂了私人飞机航站楼的迎宾员
So we paid the concierge at the private jet terminal
让他更改了租车公司
to change limo companies.
可能他告诉了别人
Maybe he told someone.
或者他可能知道工艺品在哪
Or maybe he knows where the artifact is.
赶快问她那个人的名字
Just ask her his name.
你还记得他的名字吗
Do you remember his name?
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle!
你好  我正在  我只是
Hey! I was... I just...
不敢相信她竟然把我关起来了
I can't believe she locked me up.
她还不知道
She -- she has no idea
她这是在阻止我回到她身边
she's stopping me from getting back to her.
我不知道  伙计
I don't know, man.
可能这才是你真实的生活
Maybe this is your real life.
你说你有钱有名还和这个性感警察订了婚
'Cause the one where you're rich and famous
对我来说才像是编出来
and engaged to the hot cop sounds pretty made-up to me.
我给你妈打了电话
I called your mother.
她不肯来接你
She refused to come and get you.
她坚信严厉是最好的教育方式
Oh. Well, she always did believe in tough love.
不过看起来教育得并不成功
That doesn't seem to have worked out in your case.
确实如此
No.
卡塞尔先生  你为什么对这案子这么上心
What is it with you and this case, Mr. Castle?
我是个推理作家
I'm a mystery writer and I'm compelled
我非得知道故事怎么收尾
to know how the story ends.
你的故事
With you...
以回家收尾
...going home.
你放我走吗
You're letting me go?
我也能让你在这呆一晚上
Well, I could let you stay overnight,
但那样的话我就得写书面报告了
but then I would have to do the paperwork.
不不  我
No, no. I, uh...
你说得对  我们之前见过
You know, you were right. We have met before.
-见过吗  -德里克·斯道姆小说的签售
- We have? - On a book tour for an old Derrick Storm novel.
我排队等  打算让你签名
I, uh, waited in line to get it signed...by you.
我以前很喜欢这些书
I used to love those books.
你从来没跟我说过
You never told me that.
我们才认识了一天
Well, we've only known each other for a day.
尽管感觉起来  远长于一天
Although it feels a lot longer.
跟我混  容易产生这样的错觉
I have that effect on people.
我一直有件事想问你
There's something I've been meaning to ask you.
随便问
Anything.
为什么你要让德里克·斯道姆死掉呢
Why did you kill Derrick Storm?
警监
Hey, cap.
我们有线索了
We've got something.
下次吧
Another time, I guess.
晚安  卡塞尔先生
Good night, Mr. Castle.
我们和机场迎宾员谈了谈
So we talked to the concierge at the airport.
他承认从玛利亚那收了贿赂
He admitted to taking a bribe from Maria
换了豪轿公司  但他发誓没告诉别人
to switch limo companies, but he swore he didn't tell anyone.
但当我们给他施压时
But when we held his feet to the fire,
他才把那晚看到的事情说了出来
he came clean about what he saw that night.
一辆黑色的奔驰SUV停在机场门外
A black g-wagon sitting outside the airport gates
-有两个人在里面  -就是开枪的人
- with two guys in it. - Our shooters.
他们肯定是在等甘斯勒
So they must have been waiting for Gensler,
然后就跟踪了他
and then they followed him from the airport.
是的  在等待期间
Yeah, and while they were waiting,
其中一个人出来抽烟
one of them stepped out for a smoke.
监控系统拍到了他
Surveillance caught him on camera.
我们发了全境通告  明天早上
We issued a B.O.L.O., and we're gonna run the tattoo
我们会在数据库里查找那个纹身
through the database in the morning.
好的  有消息随时通知我
All right. Why don't you gentlemen keep me apprised?
好的
Yeah.
我以为我们已达成一致  你得闪人了
I thought we agreed that you were leaving.
我对这个案子有个想法
Well, I had a thought about the case.
你跟这个案子没关系
You're not on the case.
事实上  我是在想你
Actually, I was thinking about you.
我在想我能否请你喝一杯
I was wondering if I could buy you a drink.
这是最起码的  我欠了你的情
It's the least I could do. I owe you that much.
可我觉得这不是个好...
Right. Well, I don't think that that would be a good --
你来  就告诉你我写死德里克·斯道姆的原因
And if you come, I will tell you why I killed Derrick Storm.
史上最年轻的女警监
So, the youngest woman to ever make captain.
太了不起了
That's impressive.
-没那么好啦  -不是吗
- It's not all that it's cracked up to be. - No?
不  如果你真以我为原型创造角色
No, and if you really are basing a character on me,
她肯定很没无聊
then she's gonna be boring.
我可不觉得你会无趣
Oh, I doubt you could ever be boring.
我的生活里尽是些书面报告和警局政治
Well, my life mostly consists of paperwork and politics.
你想念办案时光
Ah, you miss the streets.
说实话  我觉得
Truthfully, I-I don't think
我不该成为一个凶案警探
that I was meant to be a homicide detective.
为什么这么说
Why would you say that?
因为让我想成为警察的那个案子
Because the case that made me want to be a cop,
我一直没能侦破
I was never able to solve.
不过  话说回来
Anyway, back to you.
你为什么写死德里克·斯道姆呢
Why did you kill off Derrick Storm?
这有点复杂
Ah. It's complicated.
等一下  这是什么地方
Wait. What is this place?
-我以为这只是个约会  -你听我说完
- I thought this was a date. - Okay, hang on. Hear me out.
你还在查那个案子
You're still working the case.
听着  深红犀牛是澳大利亚
Listen. The crimson rhino is the mascot
一个橄榄球队的吉祥物
for an Australian rugby team.
如果嫌犯脖子上有那个纹身
If our suspect has a tattoo on his neck,
他肯定是球队的铁杆粉丝  我查了下
he's got to be a major fan. I looked it up.
这是纽约唯一一家
There's only one bar in New York
会现场直播他们比赛的酒吧
that plays their games live.
现在就有一场比赛
And there's one on right now.
我就知道这是个错误
I knew this was a mistake.
贝克特  等等
Beckett, wait.
是他
It's him.
待在这
Stay here.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
纽约警局  离开吧台
N.Y.P.D. Step away from the bar
把手放在我能看到的地方
and put your hands where I can see them.
当然
Sure thing.
你和我  是对好搭档唉
We make a pretty good team, you and I.
他说了什么
Well? What'd he say?
什么都没说  在他那厉害律师的建议下
Nothing, on the advice of his high-powered counsel.
-那我们接下来有什么行动  -没行动
- Okay, so what's our next move? - There is no next move.
你说你想待到案子破了再走
You asked to stick around until this case was resolved.
-现在已经破案了  -这怎么能算破案
- It's resolved. - How is it resolved?
莱恩和埃斯波西托警探在嫌犯家找到了
Detectives Ryan and Esposito found the G-wagon
那辆奔驰还有杀人凶器
and the murder weapons at our suspect's place.
一切都明了了
This is open-and-shut.
那个工艺品呢  我们得找到它
What about the artifact? We need to find it.
那个让他们偷东西的人
Whoever had them steal it,
那东西和他们早就不见了
it and they are long gone by now.
肯定有人知道它在哪里
Someone has to know where it is.
还有一个枪手
There's the other shooter.
但我们没有办法找到他
Okay, but we have no way to find him.
地方检察官会要一个认罪协议
Look, the D.A.'s gonna ask for a plea deal.
但相信我  这个嫌犯以前是军人
But trust me, this suspect's ex-military.
-他不可能供出同伴的  -就这么放手了
- He's not gonna roll. - So that's it?
这不是你的书  卡塞尔先生
This isn't one of your books, Mr. Castle.
你不会总能找到答案
You don't always get the answers.
我们已经结案了  我们赢了
We cleared the case. It's a win.
不  不能就这样了结
No, you know, that -- that can't be it.
我那个世界的凯特·贝克特绝不会就此罢休
The Kate Beckett in my world would never call this a win.
我认识的凯特·贝克特绝不会
The Kate Beckett where I come from, she would be unrelenting
碰到一点点困难就放弃
in the face of anything that's thrown in her path.
她会追寻真相  她绝对...
She would find the truth, and she would...
不会妥协
never compromise.
我不了解那个你自称来自的
I don't know what "Twilight Zone" world
《阴阳魔界》  但你并不了解我
you think you come from, but you don't know me,
也请别装作了
and don't pretend you do.
再会  卡塞尔先生
Goodbye, Mr. Castle.
我们没什么可说的了
We're done here.
-你还没睡呢  -还在洛杉矶时间呢
- You're still up. - Still on LA Time.
也对
Right.
你找到那个神秘陨石了吗
So did you find your mystic meteor?
不  没有  线索断了
No, no, um... trail went cold.
看来你要和我们困在这了
Guess you're stuck here with us then.
过来  和我坐会儿
Come, come sit with me.
来吧  给我一次机会
Come on. Just give me a chance.
看在以往的情份上
Just, um, for old times' sake.
我有个问题问你
I have a-a question for you.
希望能得到非反讽的回答
And, and I would love a-a non-ironic answer.
我们之间到底发生了什么
What happened between us?
你为什么要搬去洛杉矶
Why did you move to LA?
你心里清楚
You know why.
再讲一遍吧
Uh, tell me again.
因为你放弃了
Because you gave up.
你看了那些对你著作的负面评论
You read all those terrible reviews on your magnum opus,
心里的那道坎始终过不去
and you couldn't move past it,
我没法待在这儿看你这样
And I couldn't stick around and watch.
可你知道吗
But you know what?
我想我现在能理解了
Now I think I understand it.
为什么这么说
What do you mean?
我原本雄心壮志
I had all these plans, you know?
想要改变世界
To change the world.
我一直在为公益事业努力工作
But this nonprofit I'm working for --
可所做的一切都显得渺小虚无
Everything we do seems so small and pointless.
感觉我做什么都没有意义
It's like nothing I do matters,
那我为什么还要做呢
so why try?
亲爱的  不是的
Sweetie, no. Um...
你所做的每一件事都有意义
Everything you do matters.
每个瞬间  每个你做的决定
Every moment, every decision you make,
都影响着你周遭的人们
it affects the people around you,
都在潜移默化地改变着世界
it changes the world in a million imperceptible ways.
不论现实世界是怎样的
And no matter what your reality,
你都可以努力使它变得更好
you can make it better.
我们都可以
We both can.
我好想你  爸爸
I've missed you, dad.
亲爱的  你这是要去哪里
Darling, where are you off to?
我决定听从自己内心的声音
I'm gonna take my own advice.
我知道为什么老天把我弄到这个世界来
I know why the universe sent me to this world.
就算一生中最重要的一天搞砸了
So the most important day of our lives got screwed up.
那又怎样
Big deal.
她和我一起才更幸福
She's better off with me.
我和她在一起才更好  即使在这个世界
And I'm better off with her, even in this world.
假如我能向这个贝克特证明她有多厉害
If I can prove to this Beckett how extraordinary she is,
那她就能帮我找到这个工艺品
she can help me find that artifact,
这样我就能回去了
and I can get back home.
好了  里克的大杯卡布奇诺
There you go. It's a large cappuccino for Rick,
凯特的大杯双份无糖香草脱脂拿铁
and a large skinny latte two-pump sugar-free vanilla for Kate, right?
没错
Perfect!
太好了  非常感谢
Awesome. Thank you very much.
出租车
Taxi!
不用了  我来载你一程
That's okay. I'll give you a ride.
我讨厌这个世界
I hate this world.
别紧张  放松点
Easy. Take it easy.
就是他
That's him.
马库斯·拉克  拉克开发公司
Marcus Lark. Lark Development.
原来你就是幕后黑手
So you're behind this.
你对这个了解多少  卡赛尔先生
What do you know about this, Mr. Castle?
我知道你为了它杀了两个人
I know you killed two men for it.
你知道的可不止这些
Oh, you know more than that.
我的律师在警局无意听到你的话
My attorney overheard you at the police station.
我就让他查了下你的底细
So I had him check up on you.
过去两天的表现非常奇怪
Pretty strange behavior the last two days,
就是说要么是因为你精神不正常
which means either you're psychotic,
要么是因为这不是你的世界
or this isn't your world.
我完全不知道你在讲什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
我觉得你知道
I think you do.
你知不知道我花了多少年时间寻找这个
Do you know how many years I spent looking for this?
获取不为人知的奥秘
Hearing the whispered secrets.
古老的外星科技
Ancient alien technology.
自然发生的量子异常
Naturally occurring quantum anomalies.
神的力量
The power of god.
我毕生都在从传说中寻找真相
I spent years untangling legend from truth.
印加人认为这是通往众神的入口
The Incans believed it was a gateway to the gods,
可惜  并不是
But...it's not.
它是开启无限种可能的钥匙
It's a doorway to the infinite.
一个改变我宿命的机会
A chance to change my destiny.
它所有的秘密我都知道  卡赛尔先生
I know everything about this, Mr. Castle --
就是不知道它如何起效
Except how it works.
你有钱  事业有成  什么都有
You're rich, successful. You have everything.
为什么想要改变自己的宿命
Why would you want to change your destiny?
是个人都有后悔的事情
No man lives without regrets.
别废话了  卡塞尔先生
Now then, Mr. Castle,
到底是什么原理
How does it work?
我不知道
I don't know.
我就是拿在手上  然后就这么发生了
I was holding on to it, and it just happened.
我无意伤害你
Look, I don't want to hurt you,
但假如你不告诉  我不得不那样做
but I will if you don't tell me how it works.
我发誓  我真的不知道
I swear to you, I don't know.
-打穿他的膝盖  -什么
- Shoot out his knee. - What?
纽约警察  马上放下武器
N.Y.P.D.! Drop your weapon now!
后悔这个吧
Regret this!
-你没事吧  -没  你怎么找到我的
- Are you okay? - Yeah. How'd you find me?
我不停回想你说的关于绝不妥协的事
I couldn't stop thinking about what you said about compromise.
所以我回顾了整个调查
So I decided to retrace the investigation.
我能找到这  完全是靠运气
It's -- it's just pure luck that it brought me here when it did.
或是命运
Or fate.
你怎么在这里  他们想从你这获取什么
Why are you here? What did they want from you?
一件我并没有的东西
Something I guess I didn't have.
小心
Look out!
天啊
Oh, God.
卡塞尔先生  你救了我一命
Mr. Castle, you saved my life.
为什么
Why?
因为我爱你  凯特
Because I love you, Kate.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle?
不  求求你别死  坚持住
No, please don't go. Stay with me.
坚持住  卡塞尔
Stay with me, Castle.
卡塞尔
Castle?
贝克特
Beckett?
是你
It's you.
是我的你
My you!
我回来了
I'm back.
而且我没死
And I'm not dead.
发生什么事了  你撞到头了吗
What happened? You hit your head?
没  我昏迷了多久
No. How long was I gone?
我不知道  咱俩走散了
I don't know. We got separated.
莱恩和埃斯波西托带后援及时赶来了
Ryan and Esposito got here just in time with backup.
卡塞尔  你错过了激动人心的时刻
Hey, Castle. Missed all the excitement.
-我们超拽的  是吧  哈维  -一向如此
- We were awesome. Weren't we, Javi? - As usual.
拉克
Lark.
他才是盗窃的幕后指使
It looks like he was behind the theft.
不过他们都不肯交代
Although none of them are talking.
我们唯一没找到的
You know, the one thing that we haven't been able to find
就是手提箱里的东西
is the object that was in the briefcase.
你拿着它的时候  千万别想
When you hold this, do not wonder,
你在别的地方会过得比这好
even for a second,
一秒钟都不许想
if you'd be better off anyplace else but here.
你是说在另一个宇宙里
So in this alternate universe,
我是警监  而咱俩从来没见过
I was the captain, and you and I had never met?
你嫁给了你的工作
You were married to your work,
就跟我最初认识你的时候一样
a lot like you were when I met you.
那你没有我过得怎么样  赢了普利策奖吗
And how were you without me? Did you win the Pulitzer?
我  我还在等结果
Uh, I was...still waiting to hear.
但是没有你  我的生活远没这么幸福
But I -- my life was nowhere near as wonderful without you.
这梦还真丰富啊
That's quite a dream.
又是魔法工艺品又是平行宇宙的
Magical artifacts and parallel worlds.
是啊  还不止呢
Yeah, it was... a lot more than that.
你知道吗  我想要去的唯一一个世界
You know, the only other world I would ever
就是我赶上咱俩婚礼的世界
want to visit is the one where I made it to our wedding.
我也是
Me, too.
我知道
Yeah. I know.
所以我才一直无法入睡
It's the reason I haven't been sleeping.
我一直试图搞明白
You know, I keep trying to figure it out --
你怎么能容忍一个失去两个月人生
how do you live with the man
而且把你独自丢在婚礼上的男人呢
who's lost two months of his life and left you at the altar?
我又怎么能容忍
How do I live with...
我自己带给你那么大伤害呢
the pain I know I've caused you?
我们怎么才能越过这一切呢
How do we get past this?
我要是知道就好了
I wish I knew.
我想我找到答案了
I think I have the answer.
我们大胆向前走就对了
We just do.
那么  凯萨琳·贝克特
So, Katherine Beckett,
你愿意嫁给我吗
will you marry me?
我已经答应过你的求婚了
I've already said yes.
你愿意现在就嫁给我吗
Will you marry me right now?
谢谢你在这么短的时间里赶来
Hey! Thank you for coming on such short notice.
亲爱的  我太为你骄傲了
Oh, darling, I am so proud of you.
-妈妈  还记得那个试演吗  -记得
- Mother, you know that audition? - Yeah.
我真心认为你该去试试
I really think you should go for it.
好的
All right.
-谢谢  -好的  我带没带
- Thank you. - Okay. Do I...
带了  好的
Oh, I got it. Okay.
阿丽克西斯
Alexis.
你们准备好就可以开始了
Whenever you're ready.
好了
Yes.
从我遇见你的那刻起
The moment that I met you,
我的生活变得不同寻常
my life became extraordinary.
你教会我做更好的自己
You taught me to be my best self,
去期待明天的探险
to look forward to tomorrow's adventures.
当我脆弱的时候  你给我坚强的臂膀
And when I was vulnerable, you were strong.
我爱你  理查德·卡塞尔
I love you, Richard Castle.
我希望一生活在你温暖的笑容
And I want to live my life in the warmth of your smile
和坚实的拥抱中
and the strength of your embrace.
我发誓我将爱你
I promise you I will love you.
做你的挚友
I will be your friend
并成为你工作和生活上的伴侣  直到永远
and your partner in crime and in life, always.
从我们相遇的那刻起
The moment we met,
我的生活变得不同寻常
my life became extraordinary.
你教会我很多
You taught me more about myself
我都不知道存在的知识
than I knew there was to learn.
你是我内心的喜悦
You are the joy in my heart.
你是我每晚
You're the last person I want to see
想要相拥入眠的人
every night when I close my eyes.
我爱你  凯萨琳·贝克特
I love you, Katherine Beckett.
你是我想要倾尽此生
And the mystery of you is the one
去探索的迷
I want to spend the rest of my life exploring.
我发誓我将爱你
I promise to love you,
做你的挚友
to be your friend,
并成为你工作中
and your partner in crime
和生活上的伴侣
and life,
倾此一生
till death do us part,
直至生命尽头
and for the time of our lives.
据纽约州
By the power vested in me
赋予我的权利
by the state of New York,
我宣布你们结为夫妻
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
干杯
Cheers.
卡塞尔太太
Mrs. Castle,
可以请你跳支舞吗
may I have this dance?
没有音乐啊
There's no...music.
太完美了
It's perfect.